Have you ever attended a job interview?
你参加过求职面试吗？
For some people they can be a painful and embarrassing experience, but for others, it can be a chance to shine – a platform to perform and show off their talents.
对一些人来说，面试是一段痛苦又尴尬的经历，但对另一些人而言，这是一个大放异彩的机会——一个展示才能的平台。
But sometimes, even for the most confident candidates, things don't go to plan and the interviewee is left feeling they'd wish they had never stepped foot in the room!
不过有时候，即便是最自信的求职者，事情也可能不如预期，最后只希望自己当初没有踏进了那个房间。
The interview is a necessary part of the recruitment process, and if carried out fairly, can be a good way to select the ideal person to fill a position in a company.
面试是招聘流程中必不可少的环节，如果能公平开展，它会是公司选拔岗位理想人选的有效方式。
This can be done by just asking questions or by carrying out other tasks that test someone's competencies.
面试形式可以是提问，也可以是安排其他测试应聘者能力的任务。
It's also a chance for the interviewee to ask questions and get a feel for their potential new employer.
这同时也是应聘者提问、了解未来雇主的机会。
All this is to be expected when applying for a new job.
求职时遇到这些情况都在意料之中。
But the BBC has found there are many examples of situations where inappropriate questions have been asked and irrelevant things have been discussed.
但英国广播公司发现，有很多面试存在提问不当、讨论无关内容的情况。
Olivia Bland recently attended an interview at a technology company in the UK and claimed to have been subjected to a "brutal" two-hour job interview.
奥利维亚·布兰德近期参加了英国一家科技公司的面试，她称自己经历了一场“残酷”的两小时面试。
She said the company's CEO "tried his best to intimidate" her and that in her feedback… "He told me everything I did was wrong, everything I said, the way I sat, my body language, everything that he could do to attack me."
她说公司首席执行官“想尽办法恐吓”她，并且在反馈意见中表示“我做的所有事、说的每句话、坐姿、肢体语言，他能挑刺的地方都攻击了一遍”。
She actually got a job offer but turned it down.
她最终收到了录用通知，但还是拒绝了。
The CEO did apologise.
这位首席执行官后来也道了歉。
Other people have told the BBC about the grilling they received about their personal lives.
还有人向英国广播公司讲述了自己在面试中被追问私生活的经历。
For example, mature student Kevin Helton said "The interviewer asked, 'You used to be in the Army, how many people have you killed?'"
比如成年学生凯文·赫尔顿说：“面试官问我‘你当过兵，杀过多少人？’”
Jo Foat was asked by an interviewer to wear a large straw hat and was told "In my experience, pretty girls like you rely too much on their looks."
乔·福奥特则被面试官要求戴上一顶大草帽，对方还说“以我的经验来看，像你这样的漂亮女孩太依赖外貌了”。
There are, of course, laws against discrimination, and managers should only be asking questions that are relevant to a vacancy.
当然，有反歧视相关法律规定，面试官只应提出与岗位相关的问题。
But sometimes, according to James Reed, chairman of employment agency Reed, what may appear to be an inappropriate question is said "…to provoke you, and there's nothing illegal about provoking someone, but they can be annoying."
但招聘机构瑞德集团的董事长詹姆斯·瑞德表示，有时候一些看似不恰当的问题，其目的“是为了激怒你，激怒他人并不违法，但确实会让人不悦”。
Of course, some unconventional job interviews can be fun and are designed to put you at ease.
当然，也有一些非常规的面试形式有趣又能让人放松。
A French marketing agency is inviting applicants for an internship to discuss the opportunity over a game of Fortnite!
法国一家营销公司邀请实习申请者通过一起玩《堡垒之夜》来讨论工作机会！
Now that sounds like a fun way to develop your career!
这听起来真是开启职业生涯的有趣方式。